# Dung D. Le

Date of Birth: 21 Mar 1991

80 Stamford Road, School of Information Systems, Singapore Management University, Singapore 178902 **Contact:** • ddle.2015@phdis.smu.edu.sg • (+65) 9422-8953 • https://sites.google.com/smu.edu.sg/dungduyle/

# RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest includes *recommender systems*, *information retrieval*, and *visual analytics*. Specifically, my research works have been focusing on designing algorithms for analyzing user-generated data, understanding user preferences from the data, and applying the learnt knowledge to create user-centric applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

School of Information Systems, **Singapore Management University**,

80 Stamford Road, Singapore 178902.

PhD candidate in Data Science and Engineering Aug 2015 – (Expected date: Jul 2020)

- Research topics: Representation Learning, Recommendation Systems, Information Retrieval.
- Adviser: Hady W. Lauw.

School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics, **Hanoi University of Science and Technology**, Hanoi, Vietnam.

Degree of Engineer in Mathematics and Informatics

(5-year advanced undergraduate program).

Sep 2009 – May 2014

• Valecdictorian of School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics.

Mathematics class, Vinh Phuc Gifted high school,

Vinh Phuc, Vietnam.

Sep 2006 - Jun 2009

### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **CONFERENCE**

- [1] Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Indexable Bayesian Personalized Ranking for Efficient Top-k Recommendations*, ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM'17), full paper, Nov 2017.
- [2] Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Euclidean Co-Embedding of Ordinal Data for Multi-Type Visualization*, SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM'16), May 2016.

# AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

- Winner of Presidential Doctoral Fellowship Award, Singapore Management University, 2018.
- Recipient of SMU PhD Student Life Award, Singapore Management University, 2018.
- Conference Student Travel Awards: CIKM 2017, SDM 2016
- Postgraduate scholarship, School of Information System, Singapore Management University ( Aug 2015 ).
- Honoured as valedictorian of School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics, Hanoi University of Science and Technology (Sep 2014).
- Scholarships of Vietnam National Program for the Development of Mathematics AY13-14, AY12-13.
- Lawrence S.Ting scholarship for excellent student AY2011-12.
- Honoured as excellent student of AY2011-12.
- National Mathematics Competition for University Students (first prize 2010, second prize 2011).
- Third prize, Vietnam Mathematics Olympiad (Mar 2009 high school level).

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Living Analytics Research Centre, School of Information Systems, **Singapore Management University**,

**Position**: Research Assistant

Oct 2014 – Jun 2015

- Project: Dimensionality Reduction for Recommendation Systems.
- **Description**: Construct low-dimensional representation of users and items based on users' ordinal preferences over items for visualization and fast retrieval of data.
- Supervisor: Assistant professor Hady W. Lauw.

FPT Technology Research Institute, FPT Corporation, Hanoi, Vietnam,

**Position**: Intern, part-time employee

Nov 2013 - May 2014

• **Project**: Statistical classification techniques for question reformulation problem.

• **Description**: Develop the "question reformulation" component for the FPT Question-Answering system, using statistical classification techniques and similarity measurements.

# Mathematics Research Department, Company of Software Engineering, Hanoi, Vietnam,

Position: Intern, part-time employee

Aug 2012 – Sep 2013

• Project: Motorcycle detection, Error Correcting Codes for GSM

• **Description**: 1) Use OpenCV library to build the system to recognize motorcycle from traffic videos. 2) Build the coding and decoding channel modules for GSM system, using theory of Error Correcting Codes.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE AY2017/18-Term 1: Teaching Assistant for IS103 Computational Thinking

AY2017/18-Term 2: Teaching Assistant for IS302 Information Security and Trust

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

[1] Conference Assistant, IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence - Intelligent Agent Technology 2015 (WI-IAT'15), December 2015.

[2] External Reviewer:2017: PAKDD, DSAA2016: PAKDD, DSAA

**LANGUAGES** Vietnamese (native language).

English.

SKILLS Programming Language: MATLAB, R, Java, Python, C/C++.

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac OS.

REFERENCES Hady W. Lauw,

Assistant Professor of Information Systems, Singapore Management University, 80 Stamford Road, Singapore 178902, hadywlauw@smu.edu.sg • (+65) 6808-5277.

Page 2 of 2